Guide to the May Anti-Slavery manuscript collection, 1749-1933.
May Anti-Slavery manuscript collection
- Series IV. Correspondence and Documents from Other Abolitionists
  - R-Y
    - Saxton, J.A., February 25, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Saxton, Rufus, April 20, 1865 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Saxton, S. Willard, 1866-1868 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Schaus, William, December 24, 1872 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Schenck, Julia, September 21, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 45)
      Recommendation for a teaching position from Andrews, Jane A.
    - Scholl, Charles, May 21, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Scott, Margaret E., July 27, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 47)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Conklin, James D. and Phraner, Wilson
    - Scott, Robert Kingston, August 26, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 48)
      Orr, James Lawrence; Tomlinson, Reuben
    - Scott, Roberta D., February 1869 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - Chas. Scribner & Co., 1868-1869 (Box 23, Folder 50)
      Itemized receipts for Collins, Charles; French, Julia B.; Goodyear, C.P.; Kent, C.J.; New York Branch Freedmen's Relief Association; Norris; Richmond, E.E.
    - Charles Scribner & Co., May 29, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Scribner, Welford & Co., August 2, 1869 (Box 23, Folder 52)
      Itemized receipt for Shaw, Francis George
    - Scudder, Eliza, 1867-1871 (Box 23, Folder 52)
      Poems for Child, Lydia Maria
    - Seely, F.A., December 20, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - Semper, Dudley, December 29, 1817 (Box 23, Folder 54)
      List of slaves
    - Serment, H., April 28, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - Sewall, F.D., May 27, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - Seward, William Henry, 1850-1855 (Box 23, Folder 57-58)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller; May, Samuel Joseph
    - Sharp, Granville, February 7, 1796 (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - Sharp, Margaret, January 12, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - Shaw, Amelia, August 2, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 61)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Wright, F.G.
    - Shaw, Francis George, 1863-1869 (Box 23, Folder 62)
      Ammendment to Constitution; Receipts; McKim, James Miller
      Dutton, Kate M.; Lyon, Mary E.
    - Shepard, William, October 1, 1798 (Box 23, Folder 63)
      Indenture of apprenticeship of slave-boy Will to Oliver, John M.
    - Sheppard, Caleb Henry, June 30, 1860 (Box 23, Folder 64)
    - Sherman, F.T., January 9, 1868 (Box 23, Folder 65)
    - Shipherd, Jacob R., 1864-1867 (Box 23, Folder 66-69)
      Circular; Abbott, Lyman; McKim, James Miller; Olmsted, Frederick Law; Rust, Richard Sutton; Walden, John Morgan; unknown
      American Freedmen's Aid Commission
    - Shoemaker, Emma A., August 20, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 70)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Travis, William
    - Short, Emma J., July 1867 (Box 23, Folder 71)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Williams, P.J.
    - Simpson, Joseph, 1865-1866 (Box 23, Folder 72)
      Letter/s to Shaw, Francis George; Ward, George Cabot
    - Simpson, Matthew, 1865-1867 (Box 23, Folder 73)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller; McKim, James Miller; Thompson, J.P.
    - Slater, Lois S., August 30, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 74)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations; Teacher's certificate
    - Slink, J.W., January 5, 1868 (Box 23, Folder 75)
    - Smith, Albert W., April 25, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Minutes from a Special Meeting of The African School Society
    - Smith, Carlile, 1860 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Caroline E., Undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
      5 paychecks (one signed by Smith, Deborah)
    - Smith, D. Edson, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Applications for a teaching position; Recommendation from Whiting, S.K.
    - Smith, Deborah, 1869 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Smith, Caroline E.
    - Smith, Edward P., July 29, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Gerrit, 1843-1874 (Box 24, Folder 7-23)
      Letter/s to Bondital, J.G.; Cady, Daniel; Farmington, J.T.; Fiske, Willard; Johnson, Fanny B.; McKim, James Miller; Mattern, O.B.; Stickney, Washington; Storer, J.P.P.; Tappan, Lewis; Warren, Wilmot L.; Watsorky, John F.; Williams, O.J.
      Parker, Theodore; Stanton, Henry Brewster
    - Smith, H.E.J. (Mrs. Lloyd Pearsall), June 10, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Smith, Henry Boyton, June 12, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Smith, J. Brinton, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 26)
      Letter/s to Howard, Oliver Otis; McKim, James Miller
    - Smith, Josephine Frances, 1866-1867 (Box 24, Folder 27-28)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Foster, Amanda; Leach, F.; Newton, A.E.; Stebbins, Giles G.; 1 teacher's certificate; Letters to McKim, James Miller
    - Smith, Juliet B., 1868-1869 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Smith, Lewis B., May 16, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 29.5)
    - Smith, Lucinda, 1870 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Smith, Mary, October 22, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Smith, Samuel Alexander, 1849 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Snelling, S.O., 1867-1869 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Snelling, Mrs. S.O., August 28, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 34)
      Pease, Henry Roberts
    - Snider, N., April 2, 1831 (Box 24, Folder 35)
      Letter/s to Burnie, C.
    - Snyder, Lizzie M., September 18, 1865 (Box 24, Folder 36)
      Letter/s to Wells, H.D.
    - Spalding, Fannie E., September 19, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 37)
      Applications for a teaching position written by Beeby, W.W. and Gage, Minot G.
    - Spelman, H.B., 1864-1866 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Spring, Marcus, November 29, 1859 (Box 24, Folder 39)
      Leavitt, Joshua
    - Spring, R.B., November 9, 1859 (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Sprole, Sam M., February 14, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Stanton, Henry Brewster, January 23, 1863 (Box 24, Folder 42)
      Letter/s to Smith, Gerrit
    - Staples, A.C., January 7, 1868 (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Starr, L., November 25, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Stearns, George L., 1859-1866 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Stevens, A., July 11, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Stevens, Adam Dwight, January 17, 1860 (Box 24, Folder 47)
      Letter/s to Mrs. Watkins
    - Stevens, Thaddeus, November 27, 1862 (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Stevenson, Hannah E., 1865-1866 (Box 24, Folder 49)
      Letter/s to Frothingham, Octavius Brooks; McKim, James Miller; May, Samuel, Jr.
      Withee, Nancy Leah
    - Stewart, T.G., July 2, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - Stickney, W., 1866 (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - Still, William, 1866-1868 (Box 24, Folder 52)
      Garrett, Thomas; Linton, M.B.
    - Stille, Charles Januvay, January 13, 1863 (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - Stirling, A., April 24, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - Stockwell, G.S., March 13, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 55)
      Lewis, Abbie A.
    - Stokely, Samuel J., 1867 (Box 24, Folder 56)
      Recommendations for a teaching position from Tuille, John J. and Wake, Ransom, F.
    - Stone, Grace, January 28, 1794 (Box 24, Folder 57)
      Boswell, Ignatius
    - Stone, J.R., October 10, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 58)
    - Story, W.W., Undated (Box 24, Folder 59)
      Poem entitled "What am I?"
    - Stout, Thomas H., April 30, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 60)
      Letter/s to Am. Union Com.
    - Stoutenburgh, M.H., August 21, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 61)
      Application for a teaching position; Letter of appreciation signed by Mrs. Stoutenburgh's class
    - Stowe, Harriet Elizabeth Beecher, October 7, 1855 (Box 24, Folder 62)
      Letter/s to Johnson, Oliver
    - Stratton, Maggie E., 1869 (Box 24, Folder 63)
    - Strieby, M.E., January 12, 1869 (Box 24, Folder 64)
    - Strother, J.A., 1866 (Box 24, Folder 65)
    - Stull, Matilda R., October 14, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 66)
    - Suitterlin, J.E., 1866-1867 (Box 24, Folder 67)
      Receipts; Abbott, Lyman; McKim, James Miller
      Clark, M.C.
    - Sumner, Charles, 1836-1863 (Box 24, Folder 68-71)
    - Sweeney, F.A.B., 1866 (Box 24, Folder 72)
    - Swing, David, January 14 (n.y.) (Box 24, Folder 73)
    - Swoope, E.M., September 28, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 74)
    - Sykes (Sikes), Almira E., Undated (Box 24, Folder 75)
      Recommendations for a teaching position from Abell, Mrs. Ira H. and Jones, Jesse H.
    - Sylvester, Anna and Emily H., March 28, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 76)
    - Talbot, George F., 1866 (Box 24, Folder 77)
    - Talcott, Mrs. J.S., 1866 (Box 24, Folder 78)
    - Tappan, Lewis, 1857-1870 (Box 24, Folder 79)
      Letter/s to Garrison, Wendell Phillips; McKim, James Miller; Note
      Smith, Gerrit
    - Taws, P.H., July 25, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 80)
    - Taylor, Alonzo H., 1840-1860 (Box 24, Folder 81)
      Letter/s to Miscellaneous receipts
    - Taylor, George H., January 18, 1868 (Box 24, Folder 82)
    - Taylor, John, December 12, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 83)
    - Telfer, William Daft, February 15, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 84)
      Letter/s to Bellows, Henry Whitney
    - Thacher, Thomas Anthony, May 29, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 85)
    - Thatcher, Sarah A., Undated (Box 24, Folder 86)
    - Thayer, S.A., August 31, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 87)
    - Thayer, Sarah A., December 10, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 88)
      Application for a teaching position; Letter of appreciation from Tomlinson, Reuben
    - Thayer & Eldridge, March 29, 1860 (Box 24, Folder 89)
      Bill of sale to McKim, James Miller
    - Thomas, Jane, 1861 (Box 24, Folder 90)
    - Thomas, M.J., March 21, 1861 (Box 24, Folder 91)
    - Thomas, Rachel, June 27, 1867 (Box 24, Folder 92)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation signed by Adams, Lucy O.; Adams Sarah A.; Barrett, Gertie M.; Campbell, Addie H.; Herbert, Annie E.
    - Thomas, Samuel, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 93)
    - Thompson, Amanda M., 1869 (Box 24, Folder 94)
    - Thompson, Joseph Parrish, 1865-1868 (Box 24, Folder 95)
    - Thompson, Ruth Brown (Mrs. Oliver), March 11, 1860 (Box 24, Folder 97)
    - Thorn, Tamar, January 7, 1868 (Box 24, Folder 98)
    - Thornton, Henry, 1796 (Box 24, Folder 96)
    - Tilden, W.P., December 19, 1863 (Box 24, Folder 99)
    - Tilton, Theodore, 1860-1866 (Box 24, Folder 100)
      Grossman, H.C.
    - Timberlake, A.M., 1860-1861 (Box 24, Folder 101)
      Letter/s to Jones, John W.; McKim, James Miller
    - Tomlinson, Reuben, 1862-1869 (Box 24, Folder 102-107)
      Letter/s to Abbott, Lyman; Collins, Ellen; McKim, James Miller; Scott, Robert Kingston; Shaw, Francis George
      Orr, James Lawrence; Thayer, Sarah A.
    - Torrey, Charles T., 1844 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Towne, Laura M., 1861-1867 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Townsend, George Alfred, October 29, 1860 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Travelli, Joseph S., April 5, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Tripp, Charles J., June 6, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Tucker, Alma, June 4, 1869 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Tuke, James Hack, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Tuttle, Helen C., September 1866 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Bowers, H.C.; Dodge, Esther C.; Goodell, C.L.
    - Twitchell, T.E., November 5, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Tyler, Mary A., July 25, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Crosby, A.B.; Dewey, Fannie H.; Leeds, S.P.
    - Tyndale, Sharon, 1868 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Letter/s to Larned, Edwin C.; Gookins, S.B.; McKim, James Miller
    - Usher, Mrs. C.V., Undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Vaughan, John C., August 23, 1847 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Vaughn, Lucy M., August 8, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Hughes, John V.; Shepard, Kate A.; Way, A.J.F.
    - Vigilance Committee, December 9, 1852 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      Official report of meeting to form a Vigilance Committee (written and signed by Still, William)
    - Viziorrondez, Julio L. de, July 5, 1865 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Vliet, John, 1860-1866 (Box 25, Folder 17)
      Parrish, Joseph
    - Wadkins, Daniel, 1867-1868 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      Receipt; References
    - Wakefield, A.J., January 31, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Wakeman, Mary S., August 9, 1867 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Walden, John Morgan, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      Letter/s to Green, Jennie; McKim, James Miller
    - Walker, David Shelby, Undated (Box 25, Folder 22)
      Letter/s to Friends of the Freedman
    - Walker, Elizabeth M., February 3, 1868 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Daggett, W.S.
    - Walker, J., October 19, 1861 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Walker, S.N., February 1, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Wallcut, Robert F., 1858-1865 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Walrad, Maggie E., December 1868 (Box 25, Folder 27)
      Letter/s to Receipt; 5 paychecks
    - Joseph Walton & Co., February 25, 1867 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Ward, George Cabot, 1866-1869 (Box 25, Folder 29-33)
      Treasurer's reports; Abbott, Lyman; McKim, James Miller; Mitchell, William Foster; unknown
    - Washburn, Israel, May 8, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Watson, William L., March 30, 1867 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Weakley, S.F., January 22, 1861 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Webb, J.B., November 25, 1867 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Webb, Richard D., 1843-1868 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Warren, Joseph, 1868 (Box 25, Folder 34)
      Letter/s to Abbott, Lyman; Walden, John Morgan
    - Warren County Jail, Vicksburg, MS, June 12, 1857 (Box 25, Folder 34.1)
      Receipt for fees in arrenting Negro
    - Warriner, H.R., August 30, 1860 (Box 25, Folder 35)
      Letter/s to Grayson, F.W.
    - Webster, Daniel (fugitive slave), May 1, 1839 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Weld, Angelina Emily Grimke, 1841-1859 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Weld, Theodore Dwight, 1839-1863 (Box 25, Folder 43)
      Letter/s to Birney, William; McKim, James Miller
    - Wells, D.E., 1867 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Wells, H.D., June 6, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 45)
      Snyder, Lizzie M.
    - Welty, G.C.W., January 6, 1868 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Wessendouck, Otto, November 27, 1865 (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - West, Lucy B., 1867 (Box 25, Folder 48)
      Recommendations for a teaching position from Votey, Carles A. and Waterman, G.C.; Teacher's certificate
    - Weston, Anne W., 1862-1863 (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Weston, Emma, March 18, 1859 (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Westphal, William, January 7, 1868 (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - Wheeler, Addison, August 29, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 52)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Newton, A.E.
    - Wheeler, Benjamin Ide, Undated (Box 25, Folder 53)
      Letter/s to Harris, George William
    - Wheeler, O.C., 1866 (Box 25, Folder 54)
      Printed circular; McKim, James Miller; Shipherd, Jacob R.; unknown
    - Wheelock, E.J., Undated (Box 25, Folder 55)
      Extract from a newspaper official copy
    - Whellen, John S., April 23, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 56)
    - Whipple. George, 1866-1867 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - White, George Q., 1867 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - White, Mary J., Undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Letter/s to Freedmens Aid Commission
    - White, Samuel Stockton, 1866-1867 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - White, William A., April 26, 1844 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Whitting, W.E., 1866-1867 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Whitson, Thomas, December 10, 1860 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      Letter/s to Friends of the slave at the Philadelphia Bazaar
    - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1840-1843 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Child, Lydia Maria
    - Whittlesey, Charles, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Whittlesey, Eliphalet, 1867 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Letter/s to Wrapper; Shaw, Francis George
      Clapp, Mary (Mrs. Dexter E.)
    - Whittlesey, Mrs. R.L., January 3, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      Letter/s to Sec. Freedmans Aid Union
    - Whittlesey, R.M., 1867 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Wigham, Eliza, 1858-1867 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Wilber, John Atkins, February 6, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Wilbur, Julia A., 1866 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Wilde, Lizzie H., 1867 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      Recommendations for a teaching position from Chamberlain, J.L.; Fisher, Helen C.; Howard, C.H.; Johnson, Annie E.; Smyth, Egbert C.; Smyth, Wm.; Spear, Ellis
    - Wilder, S., January 7, 1868 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Willets, Jacob S., June 14, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Williams, C.M., 1869-1870 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Williams, Henry A., December 20, 1867 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Williams, J.H., 1869-1870 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Williams, Thomas, February 3, 1861 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Williston, L.P., March 26, 1860 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Wilson, W.P., September 5, 1882 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      Letter/s to Phillips, Wendell
    - Wing, Henry, January 15, 1868 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Winslow, Reuben, 1860-1867 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Winsor, A.B., 1867 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Wistar, Caspar, June 7, 1860 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Wister, William Ratch, November 25, 1867 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Withee, Nancy Leah, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      2 applications for a teaching position; Recommendations from Bailey, D.P.; Knowlson, W.S.; Stevenson, Hannah E.; 2 certificates of approbation
    - Woodhull, Maxwell Van Zandt, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 31)
      Johnstone, R.F.
    - Woodruff, Edwin Hamlin, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 32)
      Letter/s to Willis
      Taylor, Alonzo H.
    - Woolsey, James J., March 16, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Woolsey, Jane Stuart, February 26, 1867 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Worrell, Thomas, June 23, 1860 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Wright, James A., September 28, 1860 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Wright, Luther, February 10, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Wright, Savira, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 38)
      Letter/s to Hawkins, William George; McKim, James Miller
    - Wright, Theodore G., 1866-1867 (Box 26, Folder 39-41)
      Letter/s to Harkisheimer, W.J.; McKim, James Miller, Tomlinson, Reuben; Woolsey, James J.
      Chase, Salmon Portland; Lyon, Mary E.; Shaw, Amelia
    - Wright, William, June 22, 1861 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Yarnall, Ellis, 1863-1868 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Yeatman, James E., January 15, 1867 (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - York, Charlotte L., Undated (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - York, Emma, July 8, 1869 (Box 26, Folder 46)
      Letter/s to Mr. Lowell
    - Young, J.A., December 26, 1867 (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Younglove, Frances E., July 29, 1867 (Box 26, Folder 48)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller; Recommendations for a teaching position from Hayes, P.H.; Kendall, Alma; Russell, W.F.
    - Yulee, E., October 22, 1866 (Box 26, Folder 49)
      Letter/s to Chase, Salmond Portland